<article xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.1/xsd/JATS-journalpublishing1-mathml3.xsd" dtd-version="1.1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jchem</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Chemistry</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2090-9071</issn><issn pub-type="ppub">2090-9063</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Hindawi</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2020/3837207</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3837207</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Chemical Composition and Larvicidal Activity of Flower Extracts from <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> against <italic>Aedes</italic> (Diptera: Culicidae)</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ravindran</surname><given-names>Darvin R.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I1"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Bharathithasan</surname><given-names>Madhuri</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I1"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ramaiah</surname><given-names>Patmani</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I2"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Rasat</surname><given-names>Mohd Sukhairi Mat</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I3"><sup>3</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Rajendran</surname><given-names>Dinesh</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I4"><sup>4</sup></xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I5"><sup>5</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Srikumar</surname><given-names>Shakila</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I1"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ishak</surname><given-names>Intan H.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I4"><sup>4</sup></xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I5"><sup>5</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Said</surname><given-names>Abd Rahman</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I1"><sup>1</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-4386-3810</contrib-id><name><surname>Ravi</surname><given-names>Rajiv</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I6"><sup>6</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4283-1975</contrib-id><name><surname>Mohd Amin</surname><given-names>Mohamad Faiz</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I7"><sup>7</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="Academic Editor"><name><surname>Roussis</surname><given-names>Ioannis G.</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="I1"><sup>1</sup><addr-line>Faculty of Medicine</addr-line><addr-line>Quest International University Perak</addr-line><addr-line>Jalan Hj</addr-line><addr-line>Eusoff Housing Trust</addr-line><addr-line>Ipoh 30250</addr-line><addr-line>Perak</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">qiup.edu.my</ext-link></aff><aff id="I2"><sup>2</sup><addr-line>Faculty of Medicine</addr-line><addr-line>Universiti Kuala Lumpur Royal College of Medicine Perak (UniKL RCMP)</addr-line><addr-line>30450 Ipoh</addr-line><addr-line>Perak</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country></aff><aff id="I3"><sup>3</sup><addr-line>Faculty of Bioengineering and Technology</addr-line><addr-line>Universiti Malaysia Kelantan</addr-line><addr-line>Jeli Campus</addr-line><addr-line>Jeli</addr-line><addr-line>Kelantan</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">umk.edu.my</ext-link></aff><aff id="I4"><sup>4</sup><addr-line>School of Biological Sciences</addr-line><addr-line>Universiti Sains Malaysia</addr-line><addr-line>Minden</addr-line><addr-line>Penang</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">usm.my</ext-link></aff><aff id="I5"><sup>5</sup><addr-line>Vector Control Research Unit</addr-line><addr-line>School of Biological Sciences</addr-line><addr-line>Universiti Sains Malaysia</addr-line><addr-line>Minden</addr-line><addr-line>Penang</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">usm.my</ext-link></aff><aff id="I6"><sup>6</sup><addr-line>School of Biological Sciences</addr-line><addr-line>Faculty of Science and Technology</addr-line><addr-line>Quest International University Perak</addr-line><addr-line>Jalan Raja Permaisuri Bainun</addr-line><addr-line>Ipoh 30250</addr-line><addr-line>Perak</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">qiup.edu.my</ext-link></aff><aff id="I7"><sup>7</sup><addr-line>Faculty of Earth Science</addr-line><addr-line>Universiti Malaysia Kelantan</addr-line><addr-line>Jeli Campus</addr-line><addr-line>Jeli</addr-line><addr-line>Kelantan</addr-line><country>Malaysia</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">umk.edu.my</ext-link></aff><pub-date pub-type="publication-year"><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="archival-date"><day>1</day><month>10</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>2020</volume><history><date date-type="received"><day>17</day><month>6</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>15</day><month>9</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="pub"><day>1</day><month>10</month><year>2020</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-year>2020</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Darvin R. Ravindran et al.</copyright-holder><license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>Mosquitoes have always been a human health threat; the major global health problems caused by them are malaria, dengue fever, yellow fever, and <italic>Zika</italic> as well as several other vector-borne outbreaks. The major problems in controlling these vectors borne diseases are related to resistance to eradication measures. Different classes of insecticides used for controlling public health have raised the concern of resistant problems with mosquitoes and environmental pollution caused by the control measures. Thus, a search for alternative natural compounds is necessary for solving the insecticidal resistance problem using pesticides in the larval stage of vector development as well as creating a chemical-free environment for a healthy society. Hence, the major focus of this study is to identify the larvicidal mechanisms, metabolite, antioxidants, and chemical compounds and elucidate their structures from <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower and to test their efficacies against early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic>. <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flowers were collected from the garden of the Faculty of Medicine in International Quest University, Ipoh, Perak, and thence used for crude extraction. Further on, the metabolite test, antioxidant test, and chromatography techniques were conducted to identify the chemical composition of extracts and their chemical structures were identified using GCMS-QP2010 Ultra (Shimadzu). Next, the extracts were evaluated against the early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes</italic> mosquito vectors following the WHO procedures for larval bioassays. The larvicidal activity of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extracts evidently affected the early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes</italic> mosquito vectors. The highest larvicidal activity was observed against the early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> with the LC50 and LC95 values of 1056 and 2491&#x2009;mg/L, respectively. Meanwhile, the larvae bioassay test for <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic> recorded the LC50 and LC95 values of 1425 and 2753&#x2009;mg/L. Moreover, the results for nontarget organism test on guppy fish, <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic>, showed no mortalities with flower extracts at 2500&#x2009;mg/L, hence posing no toxic effects on fish. In this study, we have found a total of 16 chemical compounds and 6 chemical compounds have been reported to possess direct insecticidal, larvicidal, and pupicidal effects. Six chemicals with insecticidal properties were found to be glycerin, 2-hydroxy-gamma-butyrolactone, neophytadiene, <italic>n-</italic>hexadecanoic acid, <italic>cis</italic>-vaccenic acid, and octadecanoic acid with a total of 28.7&#x0025; efficacy. <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extracts also showed different types of phenols such as anthocyanins, flavonoids, and tannins. Our findings showed that the crude extract of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower bioactive molecules is effective and may be developed as biolarvicide for <italic>Aedes</italic> mosquito vector control. Furthermore, this study also provided a baseline understanding for future research work in the field of applications of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extracts for their long-term effects on human health such as a food additive, antioxidant, and cosmetic.</p></abstract><funding-group><award-group><funding-source>Quest International University</funding-source></award-group></funding-group><counts><fig-count count="4" /><table-count count="2" /><ref-count count="37" /><page-count count="9" /></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title>1. Introduction</title><p>Mosquitoes have always been a human health threat from eons; the major health problems caused by them are malaria, dengue fever, yellow fever, and <italic>Zika</italic> as well as several other vector-borne diseases. Based on World Health Organization [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>], western Pacific region, northern hemisphere reports on January 2020 dengue updates recorded were as follows: Cambodia with a higher average of 1239 cases weekly compared to the period of 2019; Malaysia with lower 4.2&#x0025; decrease weekly as 2604 cases with 9 deaths compared to the period of 2019; Philippines with 2778 cases with 10 deaths in 2020; Singapore with 2508 cases, higher compared to the period of 2019; Vietnam with 1282 weekly cases at 2020. In the southern hemisphere, Australia has recorded 78 dengue cases since the beginning of 2020 till 26 February 2020, which is lower compared to the period of 2019 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>]. Thus, dengue cases are inevitable in human community and there are many factors contributing towards this global issue.</p><p>In the current situation, only physical and chemical methods are being used to control mosquito-borne diseases. Physical methods such as mosquito bed nets, mosquito window nets at homes, and electrical mosquito rackets are only temporary solutions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>]. Besides that, the chemicals used for vector control such as temephos and pyrethroids are more well-known with some insecticides resistant challenges [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>]. Chemical insecticides are synthesized chemically based on single bioactive compounds with reference to structurally related plant compounds, which lead to the current resistance problem for all mosquitocide classes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. Only one single chemical compound can be synthesized at a time due to its high toxicity effects and the multiple plant biochemical compounds are more stable and lower in toxicity due to their synergetic effects under natural conditions. Additionally, Ravi et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>] supported the concepts of botany control mechanisms as a simple and sustainable method compared to the conventional insecticides in use.</p><p>Unlike current synthetic or chemical insecticides, the advantages of plant-based insecticides are their compositions of natural blends of multiple chemical compounds that may act synergistically on both physiological and behavioral processes of mosquitoes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6">6</xref>]. Thus, botanical-based insecticides are an alternative and accurate solution against dengue vectors of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus.</italic></p><p>In tune with the concept of a safer alternative, <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> plant has the potential as a bioinsecticide to solve the problems of resistance from a single-based chemical compound. <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> is a well-known flower in Asian countries such as Malaysia, Thailand, Philippine, India, and China and widely used in Ayurveda and Chinese medicine [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>]. Additionally, Malaysians use the extract of the flower as a food coloring to prepare a popular dish called <italic>Nasi Kerabu</italic> and Indians from the state of Kerala region consume this plant as a vegetable on a daily basis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>]. The potential compounds of this plant are prevalent in the form of polyphenols, triterpenoids, flavonoids, glycosides, anthocyanins, tannins, and steroids [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">8</xref>]. To date, only one study, Mathew et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>], has reported the basic use of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> as an <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes stephensi</italic> mosquito larvicidal but none on <italic>Ae. albopictus</italic>. According to Mathew et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>], the methanolic extract of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> showed larvicidal effectiveness; however, no mechanisms of larvicidal were explained and hence suggested improvements on further investigations pertaining to the active principles of the chemical compounds responsible for larvicidal activities. Thus, within this expansion of framework, this seems to be the first study to elucidate larvicidal mechanism, metabolite, antioxidant, and chemical compound identifications from <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower which may be responsible for <italic>Aedes</italic> larvicidal activities. The objective of this study is to identify the larvicidal mechanism, metabolite, antioxidant, chemical compounds, and the structure of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower and to test its efficacies against the early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic>.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>2. Materials and Methods</title><sec id="sec2.1"><title>2.1. Statement for Experimental Protocols</title><p>All experimental protocols mentioned in this paper were in accordance with larval susceptibility test method guidelines by the World Health Organization (WHO).</p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><title>2.2. Plant Materials</title><p><italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> used for this study was authenticated by the Herbarium of the University of Malaya with the herbarium voucher number KLU60080. <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flowers (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref>) were collected from the garden of the Faculty of Medicine in International Quest University, Ipoh, Perak. The petals of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> were washed in running tap water to remove adhered debris and soil particles and washed again with distilled water and dried in hot air oven at 70&#xb0;C until the petals were completely dry [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">10</xref>]. The dried petals were ground into fine powder by using a laboratory grinder and stored in a vacuum-tight container for further usage.</p><fig id="fig1"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Picture of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower from the field.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="3837207.fig.001" /></fig></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><title>2.3. Aqueous Extraction</title><p>Aqueous extraction was performed by maceration using 250&#x2009;ml distilled water and 50&#x2009;g of the powdered <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flowers petal. They were mixed in a 500&#x2009;ml beaker and stored in a dark area for an hour. Then, the extract was filtered using cotton wool and filter paper. The final volumes were stored in a universal bottle and maintained at 4&#xb0;C to 6&#xb0;C [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">10</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.4"><title>2.4. Methanol Extraction</title><p>Methanol extraction was performed in three different concentrations of 50&#x0025;, 70&#x0025;, and 95&#x0025;. A mixture of 5&#x2009;g powdered <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower petals and 100&#x2009;ml of respective concentration of methanol was prepared in three separate Scott bottles and covered with aluminum foil to avoid exposure to light. Later, the bottles were kept overnight in the orbital shaker for the maceration process. After 24 hours, the extract was filtered using cotton wool and filter paper by vacuum filtration method. Subsequently, they were concentrated using rotary evaporator at the temperature of 45&#xb0;C. Finally, the remained concentrated amount of extract was stored in a universal bottle and maintained at 4&#xb0;C to 6&#xb0;C [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B11">11</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.5"><title>2.5. Ethanol Extraction</title><p>Ethanol extraction was prepared in three different concentrations similar to methanol extractions of 50&#x0025;, 70&#x0025;, and 95&#x0025;. Maceration process was performed using 5&#x2009;g of powdered <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower petals and 100&#x2009;ml of respective concentrations of ethanol, mixed in three separate Scott bottles, then covered with aluminum foil to avoid exposure to light. Later, the bottles were kept at room temperature for 24 hours. The following day, all the extracts were filtered using cotton wool and filter paper by vacuum filtration method. Next, they were concentrated using rotary evaporator with the temperature at 60&#xb0;C. Finally, the concentrated extracts were stored in a universal bottle and maintained at 4&#xb0;C to 6&#xb0;C [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B11">11</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.6"><title>2.6. Petroleum Ether Extraction</title><p>Petroleum ether extraction was done with 5&#x2009;g of fresh flowers; they were cut into small pieces and soaked in a Scott bottle with 50&#x2009;ml of petroleum ether for 48 hours. Later, the extract was filtered out using filter paper and transferred to a universal bottle and stored at 4&#xb0;C to 6&#xb0;C [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B12">12</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.7"><title>2.7. Ethyl Acetate Extraction</title><p>Ethyl acetate extraction was done with 5&#x2009;g of powdered <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower petals and 100&#x2009;ml of ethyl acetate in a Scott bottle and then covered with aluminum foil to avoid exposure to light. Then, the bottle was kept at room temperature for 48 hours and after 48 hours, the extract was filtered out using cotton wool and filter paper. Finally, they were stored in a universal bottle and maintained at 4&#xb0;C to 6&#xb0;C [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B13">13</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.8"><title>2.8. Test for Flavonoid</title><p>Flavonoids identification was determined with two different chemical tests for all nine extracts; 1&#x2009;ml of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extracts was added to a test tube followed by a few drops of FeCl<sub>3</sub>; the color changes were observed. The second confirmation test for the presence of flavonoids was done in another test tube by adding 1&#x2009;ml of crude extract and few drops of 5&#x0025; of AlCl<sub>3</sub> solution and the color changes were observed [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.9"><title>2.9. Test for Anthocyanins</title><p>Anthocyanins identification was determined with two different chemical tests for all nine extracts. First, 1&#x2009;ml of crude extract was added to a test tube followed by 2&#x2009;ml of HCl and then heated for 5&#x2009;min at 100&#xb0;C, and the color changes were observed. For the second test, 1&#x2009;ml of crude extract was added to a test tube followed by 2&#x2009;ml of NaOH, and then the color changes were observed [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.10"><title>2.10. Test for Tannins</title><p>Tannins were determined with a chemical test for all nine extracts; 1&#x2009;ml of crude extract was added to a test tube followed by a few drops of FeCl<sub>3</sub>. Then the color changes were observed [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.11"><title>2.11. Test for Polyphenols</title><p>A UV-visible spectrophotometer was used to evaluate the concentrations of polyphenols present in each extract, the absorbance of which was measured at 725&#x2009;nm wavelength. All the measurements were performed in triplicate for each sample [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B13">13</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.12"><title>2.12. Paper Chromatography</title><p>Paper chromatography was used to study the fractions of the components. Chromatography paper was used to study the fractions of the extracts by placing 10&#x2009;<italic>&#x3bc;</italic>L of crude extract and allowing them to dry completely before immersing in the solvent. The solvent used in this process was the same solvent that was used for the extraction processes such as the aqueous, 50&#x0025; methanol, 70&#x0025; methanol, 95&#x0025; methanol, 50&#x0025; ethanol, 70&#x0025; ethanol, 95&#x0025; ethanol, petroleum ether, and ethyl acetate. Subsequently, the Rf values were calculated and the results interpreted comparing with the controls [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">15</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.13"><title>2.13. Thin-Layer Chromatography</title><p>Thin-layer chromatography is also a method to study the components based on the principle of fractionation. The solvent used for thin-layer chromatography is a mixture of methanol and chloroform and this process was done in a specific TLC tank. First, the TLC gel was applied on the plate and was spotted by all the crude extracts and allowed to dry for a few minutes and then the gel plate was placed into the tank to immerse with the solvent. Lastly, 1&#x0025; FeCl<sub>3</sub> was sprayed on the gel plate to identify the spots and fix the spots and Rf values were calculated based on the measurements and the results interpreted comparing with the control spots [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.14"><title>2.14. Antioxidant Activity</title><p>Based on Fu et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">16</xref>], antioxidant scavenging activity of <italic>C. ternate</italic> petals extractions was measured using DPPH solvent. To conduct the study, a 96-well plate was used to mix the extract with the DPPH solvents and other controls. Later, the plate was covered with aluminum foil and left in a dark area for 30&#x2009;minutes. During this test, ascorbic acid was used as the positive control and Tris-HCl/L buffer was used as the negative control; lastly, the color changes were observed, and OD was read using the ELISA reader at 517&#x2009;nm. The scavenging activity of DPPH radicals was calculated using the following equation:<disp-formula><mml:math display="block" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M1"><mml:mtable><mml:mlabeledtr id="EEq1"><mml:mtd><mml:mtext>(1)</mml:mtext></mml:mtd><mml:mtd><mml:mtext>scavenging&#x2009;activity</mml:mtext><mml:mfenced open="(" close=")" separators="&#x7C;"><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x0025;</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced><mml:mo>&#x3d;</mml:mo><mml:mfenced open="[" close="]" separators="&#x7C;"><mml:mrow><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mfenced open="(" close=")" separators="&#x7C;"><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>negative&#x2009;control</mml:mtext><mml:mo>&#x2212;</mml:mo><mml:mtext>sample</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mfenced open="(" close=")" separators="&#x7C;"><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>negative&#x2009;control</mml:mtext><mml:mo>&#x2212;</mml:mo><mml:mtext>positive&#x2009;control</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced><mml:mo>&#xd7;</mml:mo><mml:mn>100.</mml:mn></mml:mtd></mml:mlabeledtr></mml:mtable></mml:math></disp-formula></p></sec><sec id="sec2.15"><title>2.15. GC-MS Analysis</title><p>The GC-MS analysis was done only with the methanol (CH<sub>3</sub>OH) solvent extract and was used to determine the compounds with the analysis performed on a GCMS-QP2010 Ultra Shimadzu. The reason for only choosing methanol (CH<sub>3</sub>OH) solvent is due to its extract&#x2019;s best efficacies against <italic>Aedes</italic> larvae, as published before in several plant-based larvicidal papers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. The GCMS-QP2010 Ultra Shimadzu system was fitted with Rtx-5MS capillary column, the measurement of 30&#x2009;m&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;0.25&#x2009;mm inner diameter, and &#xd7;0.25&#x2009;<italic>&#x3bc;</italic>m film thicknesses and the maximum temperature that can be used is 370&#xb0;C, coupled with a QP2010 Ultra Shimadzu MS. Ultra-high-purity helium was used as carrier gas at a constant flow rate of 1.0&#x2009;mL/min. The injection, transfer line, and ion source temperatures were all at 280&#xb0;C. The oven temperature was programmed from 80&#xb0;C and it was held for 2&#x2009;min and raised to 280&#xb0;C at a rate of 3&#xb0;C/min. The crude samples were diluted with an appropriate solvent and filtered. The particle-free diluted crude extracts about 1&#x2009;<italic>&#x3bc;</italic>L were taken in a syringe and injected into an injector with a split ratio of 10&#x2009;:&#x2009;1. All data were obtained by collecting the full-scan mass spectra within the scan range of 40&#x2013;550&#x2009;amu. The percentage composition of the crude extract constituents was expressed as the percentage by peak area. The identification and characterization of chemical compounds in various crude extracts were based on the GC retention time [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.16"><title>2.16. Larvae Rearing</title><p>The eggs of <italic>Aedes</italic> were obtained from Vector Control Research Unit (VCRU) at Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM), Penang, Malaysia. We followed the method used by WHO [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">17</xref>] in larvae rearing. The eggs were hatched in dechlorinated water for 24 hours and were maintained at 25&#xb0;C to 30&#xb0;C (room temperature), pH of 6.95 to 7.03, and relative humidity of 80&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10&#x0025; and dissolved oxygen from 5.5 to 6.1&#x2009;mg/L in the laboratory. After five days, the early 4th instar larvae will be used for the bioassay test.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.17"><title>2.17. Larvicidal Bioassay</title><p>Larvicidal bioassays were performed in accordance with the standard World Health Organization [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">17</xref>]. Bioassays were carried out using 25 each of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic> early 4th instar larvae (homogeneous population consisting 5&#x2009;mm to 6&#x2009;mm in body length). The bioassays were replicated four times using 25 larvae for each concentration with methanol (CH<sub>3</sub>OH) as solvent control. The methanol (CH<sub>3</sub>OH) solvent extraction was chosen for larvicidal in this current study due to previous studies by Ravi et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>&#x2013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>], which showed that methanol (CH<sub>3</sub>OH) solvent had the best larvicidal effects on <italic>Aedes</italic>. During the larvae testing period, fish meal was provided. Initially, before selecting the accurate testing dose, all the larvae were subjected to a wide range of test concentrations. This step is necessary to determine the range of extract solution for larvicidal activities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. In this study, seven concentrations ranging from 500&#x2009;mg/L to 2500&#x2009;mg/L, yielding between 0 and 100&#x0025; mortality in 24 hours of exposure, were selected as test concentrations. Control solutions were prepared with 1&#x2009;ml of distilled water and 10&#x0025; of respective methanol solvent during each experimental replicate [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. The reason for using solvent control is to ensure that all test replicates are identical to plant extract solutions and to ensure that mortality results were not due to its solvents [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. Experiments were conducted at room temperature 28&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2&#xb0;C and larvae mortalities were recorded at intervals of 24 hours and 48 hours [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>]. Immobilization and total absence of movement from the larvae, even aftertouch, are the endpoint of bioassay [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5">5</xref>]. The data were analyzed by using probit analysis in IBM SPSS Statistics 24.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.18"><title>2.18. Morphological View</title><p><italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> early 4th instar larvae were observed under the optical microscope (Leica, USA), at magnification 40&#x2013;400x [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="sec2.19"><title>2.19. Nontargeted Organism Test</title><p>Guppy fish, <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic>, a total of ten fish in three replicates with 1.20&#x2009;g mean weight and 3.5&#x2009;cm mean length, were used in this test (acclimatization period of 12 days in laboratory conditions before the start of the experiment). Each treatment group has been tested with larvicidal LC<sub>95</sub> plant extract concentration dissolved in 2000&#x2009;mL dechlorinated water. A control group has also been set with only 2000&#x2009;mL of nonchlorine-treated water. The tests were performed for 24 hours with observations made at first 10 minutes and then 1, 2, 3, 6, and 24 hours. The mortality and observable abnormalities of fish were recorded. Test conditions of water such as pH, water temperature, and dissolved oxygen were recorded during the start and end of the experiment [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>].</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>3. Results</title><sec id="sec3.1"><title>3.1. Metabolite Study</title><p>Based on the S1 and S2 (refer to supplementary file (available <xref ref-type="sec" rid="supplementary-material-1">here</xref>)), the absorbance showed a higher presence of anthocyanin, flavonoids, and tannins in the <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts of 95&#x0025; methanol compared to other extractions.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.2"><title>3.2. Paper Chromatography</title><p>All the values in S3 (refer to supplementary file) show the three-retention factor, Rf values present in <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts in all the solvents used for the extraction process. The use of methanol solvent showed higher retention factor, Rf values compared to other solvents.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.3"><title>3.3. Thin-Layer Chromatography</title><p>All the values in S4 (refer to supplementary file) show the three-retention factor, Rf values present in <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts in all the solvents used for the extraction process. The use of methanol and ethanol solvent showed approximately similar retention factor, Rf values.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.4"><title>3.4. Antioxidant Activity</title><p>2,2-Diphenyl-1-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH) was used to identify the presence of antioxidant property in each extract. Based on S5 (refer to supplementary file (available <xref ref-type="sec" rid="supplementary-material-1">here</xref>)), the graph shows the extracts with high antioxidant property and low antioxidant property. The extract that carried the highest antioxidant property was aqueous in nature.</p></sec><sec id="sec3.5"><title>3.5. GC-MS Analysis and Identification of Compounds</title><p>GC-MS analysis of methanol solvent extracts of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower showed 16 peaks which indicate the presence of 16 phytochemical compounds S6 (refer to supplementary file). Comparing the mass spectra of the constituents with the NIST 08 library, 16 compounds were characterized and identified (Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="tab1">1</xref>). The major three chemical compounds in the extracts showing the highest peaks were acetic acid, 1-(2-methyltetrazol-5-yl) ethenyl ester (16.5&#x0025;), 4H-pyran-4-one, 2,3-dihydro-3,5-dihydroxy-6-methy (13.9&#x0025;), and di-glyceraldehyde dimer (12.4&#x0025;). The attached S6 (refer to supplementary file) contains the NIST 08 library search for chemical compound structures and details.</p><table-wrap id="tab1"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Chemical compounds for <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower.</p></caption><table><thead><tr><th align="left">S/N</th><th align="center">RT</th><th align="center">Area</th><th align="center">Area (&#x0025;)</th><th align="center">Compound name</th><th align="center">Activity</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">1</td><td align="center">4.256</td><td align="center">42912</td><td align="center">9.631</td><td align="center">Glycerin</td><td align="center">Pupicidal and larvicidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B18">18</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">2</td><td align="center">4.65</td><td align="center">9713</td><td align="center">2.18</td><td align="center">2,4-Dihydroxy-2,5-dimethyl-3(2H)-furan-3-one</td><td align="center">Anthelminthic [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B19">19</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">3</td><td align="center">4.823</td><td align="center">21616</td><td align="center">4.851</td><td align="center">2-Hydroxy-gamma-butyrolactone</td><td align="center">Insecticidal metabolite [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">21</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">4</td><td align="center">6.927</td><td align="center">73492</td><td align="center">16.494</td><td align="center">Acetic acid, 1-(2-methyltetrazol-5-yl)ethenyl ester</td><td align="center">Agricultural [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B22">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">5</td><td align="center">8.602</td><td align="center">55658</td><td align="center">12.491</td><td align="center">dl-Glyceraldehyde dimer</td><td align="center">Antioxidant [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B23">23</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">6</td><td align="center">8.84</td><td align="center">15893</td><td align="center">3.567</td><td align="center">Alpha-amino-gamma-butyrolactone</td><td align="center">Antioxidant and cytotoxic [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B24">24</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">7</td><td align="center">9.151</td><td align="center">61940</td><td align="center">13.901</td><td align="center">4H-pyran-4-one, 2,3-dihydro-3,5-dihydroxy-6-methy</td><td align="center">Antioxidant [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B25">25</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">8</td><td align="center">12.709</td><td align="center">46623</td><td align="center">10.463</td><td align="center">1,2,3-Propanetriol, monoacetate</td><td align="center">Antimicrobial [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B26">26</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">9</td><td align="center">14.048</td><td align="center">16670</td><td align="center">3.741</td><td align="center">1,2-Dioxolan-3-one, 5-ethyl-5-methyl-4-methylene-</td><td align="center">Antioxidant [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B27">27</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">10</td><td align="center">20.099</td><td align="center">3546</td><td align="center">0.796</td><td align="center">4-Ethylamino-<italic>n</italic>-butylamine</td><td align="center">Herbicidal and insect lighting coating material [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B28">28</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">29</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">11</td><td align="center">20.22</td><td align="center">30010</td><td align="center">6.735</td><td align="center">1,6-Anhydro-2,4-dideoxy-beta- D-ribo-hexopyranose</td><td align="center">Pesticidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">30</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">12</td><td align="center">30.899</td><td align="center">3872</td><td align="center">0.869</td><td align="center">2-Propenoic acid, tridecyl ester</td><td align="center">Antifungal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B31">31</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">13</td><td align="center">36.132</td><td align="center">3771</td><td align="center">0.846</td><td align="center">Neophytadiene</td><td align="center">Larvicidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">14</td><td align="center">40.342</td><td align="center">31374</td><td align="center">7.041</td><td align="center"><italic>n-</italic>Hexadecanoic acid</td><td align="center">Larvicidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">15</td><td align="center">45.991</td><td align="center">26925</td><td align="center">6.043</td><td align="center"><italic>cis</italic>-Vaccenic acid</td><td align="center">Larvicidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B32">32</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left">16</td><td align="center">46.693</td><td align="center">1566</td><td align="center">0.351</td><td align="center">Octadecanoic acid</td><td align="center">Larvicidal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>S/N: signal noise; RT: retention time.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="sec3.6"><title>3.6. Larvicidal Bioassay</title><p>The bioassay testing from methanol solvent extracts of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower was tested at 300&#x2009;mg/L, 500&#x2009;mg/L, 1000&#x2009;mg/L, 1500&#x2009;mg/L, 1700&#x2009;mg/L, 2000&#x2009;mg/L, and 2500&#x2009;mg/L. The entire larvae bioassay test with <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts showed a significant increase in mortality percentage with the increase of concentration. On comparing the tested flower extracts, maximum larvicidal activity was observed to be against early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> with the LC50 and LC95 values of 1056 and 2491&#x2009;mg/L, respectively (Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="tab2">2</xref>). Meanwhile, the larvae bioassay test for <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic> recorded the LC50 and LC95 values of 1425 and 2753&#x2009;mg/L (Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="tab2">2</xref>). Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref> shows the graphical representation of larvae mortality rate between <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic>. Finally, the results for nontarget organism test on guppy fish, <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic>, showed no mortalities with plant extracts at 2500&#x2009;mg/L, posing no toxic effects on this fish (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref>). The 95&#x0025; confidence limits LC50 (95&#x0025; CI) and LC95 (95&#x0025; CI), chi-square, and degree of freedom (<italic>df</italic>) values were also calculated (Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="tab2">2</xref>). In the control assay, there was no significant mortality.</p><table-wrap id="tab2"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Larvicidal activity of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extracts against early 4th instar larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic>.</p></caption><table><thead><tr><th align="left">Larvae</th><th align="center">LC<sub>50</sub> (mg/L) (95&#x0025; LCL-UCL)</th><th align="center">LC<sub>95</sub> (mg/L) (95&#x0025; LCL-UCL)</th><th align="center"><italic>&#x3c7;</italic><sup>2</sup></th><th align="center"><italic>df</italic></th><th align="center"><italic>R</italic></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left"><italic>A. aegypti</italic></td><td align="center">1056 (981&#x2013;1121) <italic>Y</italic>&#x2009;&#x3d;&#x2009;&#x2212;14.142&#x2009;&#x2b;&#x2009;4.722<italic>X</italic></td><td align="center">2491 (2094&#x2013;2641) <italic>Y</italic>&#x2009;&#x3d;&#x2009;&#x2212;14.142&#x2009;&#x2b;&#x2009;4.722<italic>X</italic></td><td align="center">30<sup>&#x2217;</sup></td><td align="center">22</td><td align="center">0.667</td></tr><tr><td align="left"><italic>A. albopictus</italic></td><td align="center">1425 (1352&#x2013;1491) <italic>Y</italic>&#x2009;&#x3d;&#x2009;&#x2212;19.682&#x2009;&#x2b;&#x2009;6.282<italic>X</italic></td><td align="center">2753 (2374&#x2013;2881) <italic>Y</italic>&#x2009;&#x3d;&#x2009;&#x2212;19.682&#x2009;&#x2b;&#x2009;6.282<italic>X</italic></td><td align="center">30<sup>&#x2217;</sup></td><td align="center">22</td><td align="center">0.882</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p><italic>N</italic><sub><italic>a</italic></sub>: total number of mosquitoes larvae used, <italic>n</italic>&#x2009;&#x3d;&#x2009;25 each with 4 replicates; LC50: lethal concentration 50&#x0025; mortality; LC95: lethal concentration 95&#x0025; mortality; LCL: lower confidence limits; UCL: upper confidence limits; <italic>&#x3c7;</italic><sup>2</sup>: Pearson chi-square; <italic>df</italic>: degrees of freedom; <italic>R:</italic> Pearson&#x2019;s <italic>R</italic> (note: chi-square values with an asterisk are significant (<inline-formula><mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M2"><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mo>&#x3c;</mml:mo><mml:mn>0.05</mml:mn></mml:math></inline-formula>)).</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><fig id="fig2"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Comparison of larvae mortality rate between <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> and <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic> for <italic>various Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extract concentrations.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="3837207.fig.002" /></fig><fig id="fig3"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Guppy fish, <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic>, toxicity test with <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="3837207.fig.003" /></fig></sec><sec id="sec3.7"><title>3.7. Morphological View</title><p>The morphological view from Figures <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(a) and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(b) is indicating the presence of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts in the midgut content by dark greenish color of extracts.</p><fig id="fig4"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Morphological midgut content induced by <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic>. (a) Midgut content view in larvae of <italic>Aedes aegypti.</italic> (b) Midgut content view in larvae of <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic>. <italic>Note</italic>. Arrows indicate the plant extracts (dark greenish color); GC: gut content (after 24 hours).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="3837207.fig.004" /></fig></sec></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>4. Discussion</title><p>The results of this study have shown that the phytochemical compounds extracted from <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower may have innovative and integrated property of a bio insecticidal agent. Thus, this study intends to highlight the role of the extract as an alternative control measure against <italic>Aedes</italic> when compared to the synthetic insecticides. Additionally, <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts may be more effective than single-based active compound due to their active ingredients&#x2019; synergisms which may be effective in managing resistant population of mosquitoes. In this study, we have found a total of 16 chemical compounds and 6 chemical compounds have been reported to possess direct insecticidal, larvicidal, and pupicidal effects. The six chemicals used for their insecticidal properties in previous studies were glycerin, 2-hydroxy-gamma-butyrolactone, neophytadiene, n-hexadecanoic acid, <italic>cis</italic>-vaccenic acid, and octadecanoic acid constituting a total of 28.7&#x0025;. All these chemical components have direct larvicidal activity and there are many more compounds which may act synergistically in the larvicidal activity. Similarly, Ravi et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>] have also discussed the synergetic effects of multiple chemical compounds from plant extract against <italic>Aedes</italic> larvae.</p><p>A previous study by Mathew et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>] on <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> extracts did not show the mechanism of larvicidal activity. However, to elucidate the effects of larvicidal mechanisms, this current study has shown the effect of the extract on the midgut after ingestion as shown in the morphological picture (Figures <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(a) and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(b). The ingested plant extracts shown in Figures <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(a) and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref>(b) were quite similar to the previous study done with <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> plant extracts (green color) in the larvae midgut content after 24 hours of ingestion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]. Thus, it can be congruently observed that the <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extract ingestion mechanism was used in the killing effect of <italic>Aedes</italic> larvae. As per the results shown by the <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extract on the guts of larvae, the potential commercialization of this extract would be done using liquid-based techniques. An example of a similar possible commercial application done in the past was &#x201c;Dalmatian Powder,&#x201d; dissolved in liquid for its application [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B33">33</xref>]. Additionally, the storage condition of the crude extract in this study was at &#x2212;4&#xb0;C before its application under room temperature. Similarly, Ravi et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>] have prevented the degradation of crude extract by storing it at &#x2212;4&#xb0;C before its application.</p><p>The residual activity of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extract showed up to 48 hours in water. Moreover, Ullah et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">34</xref>] recorded that there are five different plant species with residual activities against <italic>Culex quinquefasciatus</italic> up to 72 hours upon their application. Elsewhere, a study on <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> extract has suggested that 48 hours of residual activity in water and plant-based applications was much shorter in their residual effects compared to synthetic pesticides [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]. Thus, it can be concluded that plant-based insecticides possess lesser residual activity compared to synthetic chemicals. Additionally, the <italic>C. ternatea</italic> plant extracts did not possess any toxic effects on fish. According to Pereira and Oliveira [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">35</xref>], <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic> has important potential effects to predate <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> larvae and this will help to eliminate the breeding ground of larvae. Thus, without the toxic effects of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extracts on <italic>Poecilia reticulate</italic>, we could integrate both applications using <italic>C. ternatea</italic> and fish to control <italic>Aedes</italic> larvae. In addition to that, the toxicity results in this current study were also similar to the previous study based on <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> plant [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]. Thus, the use of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extract is not toxic for the environment and it is safer to be applied compared to chemical application in controlling <italic>Aedes</italic> larvae.</p><p>In addition to that, the metabolite study of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> extracts showed different types of phenols such as anthocyanin, flavonoids, and tannins. Anthocyanin, flavonoids, and tannins were present in both methanol and ethanol extracts of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> compared to other extracts (Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="tab1">1</xref>). Divya et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>] reported similar findings on <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> blue and white flowered leaves which recorded the highest polyphenol isolation using methanol extraction techniques. Moreover, this was further proven with thin-layer chromatography and paper chromatography techniques, whereby all the extracts were found to have three spots upon fixing with ferric chloride (FeCl<sub>3</sub>). Concurrently, Sunita et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">36</xref>] have also reported the same results with medicinal plant using ferric chloride (FeCl<sub>3</sub>) to identify only phenolic compounds on chromatography paper. Finally, the antioxidant test for <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts showed that aqueous extract has the highest antioxidant property compared to other extraction methods. The aqueous extract was found to have high antioxidant because water extract can absorb antioxidant compound better than chemicals [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">37</xref>].</p><p>Thus, it can be concluded that <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extract-based insecticides may possess lesser residual activity compared to synthetic chemicals and contain multiple natural chemical compounds which may solve the single-based insecticide-resistant problems. Finally, although <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts may be used as bio&#x2010;larvicides, future testing would have to be conducted to validate their long-term effects on human health and other organisms in the environment.</p></sec><sec id="sec5"><title>5. Conclusion</title><p>We can conclude that this current study has shown the colossal effectiveness of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> flower extracts against major dengue fever vectors during the early 4th instar larval stages. Additionally, current findings showed the bioactive molecules even from crude extracts to be effective and may be developed as biolarvicides for <italic>Aedes</italic> mosquito vector control programs. Furthermore, this study also provided a baseline understanding for future research work on the field of applications of <italic>C. ternatea</italic> flower extracts which could be tested for their long-term effects applicable to other industries encompassing all aspects of human health.</p></sec></body><back><sec sec-type="data-availability"><title>Data Availability</title><p>The data used to support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author upon request.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement"><title>Conflicts of Interest</title><p>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The authors would like to acknowledge the Quest International University internal funds and also thank university staffs and research students who have contributed to this work.</p></ack><sec sec-type="supplementary-material" id="supplementary-material-1"><title>Supplementary Materials</title><supplementary-material id="supp-1" xlink:href="http://downloads.hindawi.com/journals/jchem/2020/3837207.f1.pdf" mimetype="application/pdf"><label>Supplementary Materials</label><caption><p>The NIST 08 library search for chemical compound structures and details.</p></caption></supplementary-material></sec><ref-list><ref id="B1" content-type="book"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>WHO</surname></name></person-group><source><italic>Update on the Dengue Situation in the Western Pacific Region: Northern Hemisphere Cambodia</italic></source><year>2020</year><publisher-loc>Geneva, Switzerland</publisher-loc><publisher-name>World Health Organization</publisher-name></element-citation></ref><ref id="B2" content-type="article"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ravi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zulkrnin</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shaida</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><etal /></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of two different solvents for <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> extracts on chemical compositions and larvicidal activity against <italic>Aedes albopictus</italic> (Diptera: Culicidae)</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Chemistry</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>2018</volume><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">7453816</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2018/7453816</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85057410251</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B3" content-type="article"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zulkrnin</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shaida</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rozhan</surname><given-names>N. N.</given-names></name><etal /></person-group><article-title>Larvicidal effectiveness of <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> against <italic>Aedes aegypti</italic> (Diptera: Culicidae) with its effects on larval morphology and visualization of behavioural response</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Parasitology Research</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>2018</volume><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1383186</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2018/1383186</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85049828941</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B4" content-type="article"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ravi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zulkrnin</surname><given-names>N. S. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rozhan</surname><given-names>N. N.</given-names></name><etal /></person-group><article-title>Chemical composition and larvicidal activities of <italic>Azolla pinnata</italic> extracts against <italic>Aedes</italic> (Diptera: Culicidae)</article-title><source><italic>PLoS One</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>13</volume><issue>11</issue><pub-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">e0206982</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0206982</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85056228166</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B5" content-type="article"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ravi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ishak</surname><given-names>I. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mohd Amin</surname><given-names>M. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rasat</surname><given-names>M. S. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Salam</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mohd Amin</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Nano-synthesized silver particles and <italic>Azolla Pinnata</italic> extract Larvicidal effects against aedes aegypti (diptera: culicidae)</article-title><source><italic>International Journal of Advanced Science and Technology</italic></source><year>2020</year><volume>29</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>3420</fpage><lpage>3427</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="B6" content-type="article"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ghosh</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chowdhury</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chandra</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Plant extracts as potential mosquito larvicides</article-title><source><italic>The Indian Journal of Medical Research</italic></source><year>2012</year><volume>135</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>581</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="B7" content-type="article"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Arumugam</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Manjula</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Paari</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A review: anti diabetic medicinal plants used for diabetes mellitus</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Acute Disease</italic></source><year>2013</year><volume>2</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>196</fpage><lpage>200</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/s2221-6189(13)60126-2</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B8" content-type="article"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>P. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>N. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Heinrich</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The ayurvedic medicine <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic>&#x2014;from traditional use to scientific assessment</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Ethnopharmacology</italic></source><year>2008</year><volume>120</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>291</fpage><lpage>301</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2008.09.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-56349086499</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B9" content-type="article"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mathew</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Anitha</surname><given-names>M. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bala</surname><given-names>T. S. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sivakumar</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Narmadha</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kalyanasundaram</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Larvicidal activity of <italic>Saraca indica, Nyctanthes arbor-tristis</italic>, and <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> extracts against three mosquito vector species</article-title><source><italic>Parasitology Research</italic></source><year>2009</year><volume>104</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1017</fpage><lpage>1025</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00436-008-1284-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-62949092163</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B10" content-type="article"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Leong</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Williamkoh</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antioxidant activities of aqueous extracts of selected plants</article-title><source><italic>Food Chemistry</italic></source><year>2006</year><volume>99</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>775</fpage><lpage>783</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.07.058</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-33646582005</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B11" content-type="article"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Anand</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Doss</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nandagopalan</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antibacterial studies on leaves of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> linn.&#x2014;a high potential medicinal plant</article-title><source><italic>International Journal of Applied Biology and Pharmaceutical Technology</italic></source><year>2011</year><volume>2</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>453</fpage><lpage>456</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="B12" content-type="article"><label>12</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mathew</surname><given-names>T. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Benny</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Flowers with antibacterial property&#x2014;a survey in Meenachil Taluk</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Pharmaceutical, Chemical and Biological Sciences</italic></source><year>2016</year><volume>4</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>252</fpage><lpage>261</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="B13" content-type="article"><label>13</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ismail</surname><given-names>A. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Idris</surname><given-names>A. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Amina</surname><given-names>M. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Audu</surname><given-names>S. A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phytochemical studies and thin layer chromatography of leaves and flower extracts of Senna siamea lam for possible biomedical applications</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Pharmacognosy and Phytotherapy</italic></source><year>2015</year><volume>7</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>18</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/jpp2014.0337</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-84925450224</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B14" content-type="article"><label>14</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Divya</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Anbumalarmathi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sharmili</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phytochemical analysis, antimicrobial and antioxidant activity of <italic>Clitoria ternatea</italic> blue and white flowered leaves</article-title><source><italic>Advances in Research</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>14</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.9734/air/2018/39030</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B15" content-type="article"><label>15</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ferry</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Larson</surname><given-names>R. A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A mixed solvent for rapid TLC analysis of phenolic compounds</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Chromatographic Science</italic></source><year>1991</year><volume>29</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>476</fpage><lpage>477</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/chromsci/29.11.476</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-0026253879</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B16" content-type="article"><label>16</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antioxidant properties and involved compounds of daylily flowers in relation to maturity</article-title><source><italic>Food Chemistry</italic></source><year>2009</year><volume>114</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1192</fpage><lpage>1197</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2008.10.072</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-60249088447</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B17" content-type="book"><label>17</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>World Health Organization</surname></name></person-group><source><italic>Guidelines for Laboratory and Field Testing of Mosquito Larvicides</italic></source><year>2005</year><publisher-loc>Geneva, Switzerland</publisher-loc><publisher-name>World Health Organization</publisher-name></element-citation></ref><ref id="B18" content-type="misc"><label>18</label><element-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Principato</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pupicidal and larvicidal composition</article-title><year>2010</year><comment>US20100310685A1</comment></element-citation></ref><ref id="B19" content-type="article"><label>19</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Koorse</surname><given-names>K. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Samraj</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>John</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><etal /></person-group><article-title>Anthelmintic activity of fruit extract and fractions of <italic>Piper longum</italic> L. In vitro</article-title><source><italic>Pharmacognosy Journal</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>10</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>333</fpage><lpage>340</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5530/pj.2018.2.57</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85048176804</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B20" content-type="article"><label>20</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bharali</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gamo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Das</surname><given-names>A. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tag</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Baruah</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kakati</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phytochemical and biochemical study of four legume plants with detergent and anti-lice properties from the Eastern Himalayan region of India</article-title><source><italic>Current Science</italic></source><year>2017</year><volume>113</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>1434</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">00113891</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.18520/cs/v113/i07/1434-1439</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85030543523</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B21" content-type="article"><label>21</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vats</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of bioactive compounds and antioxidant potential of hydroethanolic extract of <italic>Moringa oleifera</italic> Lam. from Rajasthan, India</article-title><source><italic>Physiology and Molecular Biology of Plants</italic></source><year>2017</year><volume>23</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>239</fpage><lpage>248</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12298-016-0407-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85008208763</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B22" content-type="misc"><label>22</label><element-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takayanagi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Agricultural chemicals formulation for rice paddy field, preparation thereof and the method for scattering the same</article-title><year>2002</year><comment>US6486095B1</comment></element-citation></ref><ref id="B23" content-type="article"><label>23</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ahmed</surname><given-names>S. H.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of antioxidant and anti-mutagenic activity of naturally fortified honey with <italic>curcuma longa</italic> extract</article-title><source><italic>International Journal of Biosciences (IJB)</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>13</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>248</fpage><lpage>256</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.12692/ijb/13.1.248-256</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B24" content-type="article"><label>24</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Padmashree</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ashwathanarayana</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Raja Naika</surname><given-names>R. B.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antioxidant, cytotoxic and nutritive properties of <italic>Ipomoea staphylina</italic> Roem &#x26; Schult. plant extracts with preliminary phytochemical and GCMS analysis</article-title><source><italic>Asian Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>4</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>473</fpage><lpage>492</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.31024/ajpp.2018.4.4.16</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B25" content-type="article"><label>25</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cechovska</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cejpek</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Konecny</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Velisek</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>On the role of 2,3-dihydro-3,5-dihydroxy-6-methyl-(4<italic>H</italic>)-pyran-4-one in antioxidant capacity of prunes</article-title><source><italic>European Food Research and Technology</italic></source><year>2011</year><volume>233</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>367</fpage><lpage>376</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00217-011-1527-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-84860389147</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B26" content-type="misc"><label>26</label><element-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Heeres</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Backx</surname><given-names>L. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thijssen</surname><given-names>J. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Knaeps</surname><given-names>A. G.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>[[4-[4-(4-phenyl-1-piperazinyl)phenoxymethyl]-1, 3-dioxolan-2-yl] methyl]-1h-imidazoles and 1h-1,2,4-triazoles having anti-microbial properties</article-title><year>1988</year><comment>PT78156A</comment></element-citation></ref><ref id="B27" content-type="article"><label>27</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Prabakaran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ramu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Veerappan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pemiah</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kannappan</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of different solvents on volatile and non-volatile constituents of red bell pepper (<italic>Capsicum annuum L</italic>.) and their in vitro antioxidant activity</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Food Measurement and Characterization</italic></source><year>2017</year><volume>11</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1531</fpage><lpage>1541</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11694-017-9532-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85019138929</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B28" content-type="misc"><label>28</label><element-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Van Kleef</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Insect control lighting device</article-title><year>2019</year><comment>US Patent 20180116196A1</comment></element-citation></ref><ref id="B29" content-type="misc"><label>29</label><element-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cleveland</surname><given-names>J. D.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Herbicidal N-substituted-dithioamino and N-substituted-oxythioamino triazines</article-title><year>1975</year><comment>US Patent 3909237A</comment></element-citation></ref><ref id="B30" content-type="article"><label>30</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Henzell</surname><given-names>R. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Furneaux</surname><given-names>R. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tyler</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>An evaluation of the herbicidal and plant growth regulatory activity of a novel class of carbohydrate-derived 6,8-dioxabicyclo[3.2.1]octanes</article-title><source><italic>Pesticide Science</italic></source><year>1990</year><volume>30</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>59</fpage><lpage>66</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ps.2780300107</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-84987055065</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B31" content-type="article"><label>31</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sangeetha</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Amirtham</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Antifungal bioactive compounds from Chinese caterpillar fungus (<italic>Ophiocordyceps sinensis</italic> (Berk.) GH Sung et al.) against plant pathogens</article-title><source><italic>Madras Agricultural Journal</italic></source><year>2015</year><volume>102</volume></element-citation></ref><ref id="B32" content-type="article"><label>32</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nyamoita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mbwambo</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ochola</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Innocent</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lwande</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hassanali</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Chemical composition and evaluation of mosquito larvicidal activity of <italic>Vitex payoffs</italic> extracts against <italic>Anopheles gambiae</italic> Giles SS larvae</article-title><source><italic>Spatula DD</italic></source><year>2013</year><volume>3</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>113</fpage><lpage>120</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5455/spatula.20130806054707</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B33" content-type="article"><label>33</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pavela</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>History, presence and perspective of using plant extracts as commercial botanical insecticides and farm products for protection against insects&#x2014;a review</article-title><source><italic>Plant Protection Science</italic></source><year>2016</year><volume>52</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>229</fpage><lpage>241</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.17221/62/2015-pps</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-84954516435</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B34" content-type="article"><label>34</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ullah</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ijaz</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mughal</surname><given-names>T. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zia</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Larvicidal activity of medicinal plant extracts against <italic>Culex quinquefasciatus</italic> Say. (Culicidae, Diptera)</article-title><source><italic>International Journal of Mosquito Research</italic></source><year>2018</year><volume>5</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>47</fpage><lpage>51</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="B35" content-type="article"><label>35</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pereira</surname><given-names>B. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Oliveira</surname><given-names>E. A. d.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Determinacao do potencial larvofago de <italic>Poecilia reticulata</italic> em condicoes domesticas de controle biologico</article-title><source><italic>Cadernos Saude Coletiva</italic></source><year>2014</year><volume>22</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>241</fpage><lpage>245</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1590/1414-462x201400030004</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B36" content-type="article"><label>36</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sunita</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sonam</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ganesh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Gas chromatography-mass spectrometry analysis of an endangered medicinal plant, <italic>Sarcostemma viminale</italic> (L.) R. BR. From thar desert, Rajasthan (India)</article-title><source><italic>Asian Journal of Pharmaceutical and Clinical Research</italic></source><year>2017</year><volume>10</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>210</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22159/ajpcr.2017.v10i9.18707</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="other">2-s2.0-85029593282</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="B37" content-type="article"><label>37</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bouabid</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lamchouri</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Toufik</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Faouzi</surname><given-names>M. E. A.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Phytochemical investigation, in vitro and in vivo antioxidant properties of aqueous and organic extracts of toxic plant: <italic>Atractylis gummifera</italic> L.</article-title><source><italic>Journal of Ethnopharmacology</italic></source><year>2020</year><volume>253</volume><fpage>112640</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2020.112640</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>